Previously on Transformers Prime...
在上一集里
It appears the ship now possesses a will of its own.
看上去飞船有了自己的意识！
It also seems to be doing a better job of decoding the project Iacon database than we were.
而且它似乎比我们更擅长破译铁堡计划的数据库
Regain control of this vessel by any means necessary.
不管用什么手段 夺回战舰的控制权！
This could be our only chance to slip aboard and download the Iacon database.
这或许是我们登舰下载铁堡数据库的唯一机会
Why is the warship heading for Manhattan?
为什么这艘战舰在飞向曼哈顿？
The Iacon relics landed on Earth eons ago,
铁堡的圣物在很久以前失落到了地球上
long before the city was built atop it.
远早于城市建立的时间
Agent Fowler! That's all that's been downloaded?!
福勒探员 才下载了这么点？
Run for it!
快跑！
Come on. Here's our ride!
快 我们快走！
The download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete,
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
Then we must act quickly,
那我们必须尽快行动
for Megatron will not hesitate to obtain the potential doomsday devices which lie at the site of each.
因为 威震天会毫不犹豫地夺取那里的超级武器…
If we are to have any hope of recovering the Iacon relics before the Decepticons do,
如果我们想赶在霸天虎之前得到铁堡的遗产
we must divide our resources.
我们就必须分头行动
But Optimus,
但是擎天柱
when it comes to numbers, we are already at a grave disadvantage.
我们人手本来就不足…
Under the circumstances, swiftness of action is paramount.
在目前情况下 快速应变最为重要
This is one race that we absolutely cannot afford to lose.
这是一场我们输不起的竞赛
Dispatching multiple squadrons will enable us to pursue all four coordinates simultaneously.
派出多支小队 同时前往这四个地点
Lord Megatron, I have assembled the mining detail
威震天陛下 您要的第一处坐标具体发掘方案
Breakdown and I enjoyed previous success retrieving Iacon relics.
上次我和打击成功收回了铁堡的遗产
In memory of my fallen comrade, I intend to do the same again.
这次我也会用成功向死去的战友致敬
This is a mission,
这是个任务
not one of your racing excursions.
不是让你出去飙车兜风
Stop your preening!
少在那儿夸夸其谈！
Move quickly and operate with a surgeon's skill!
服从军令 立即去执行！
Do you understand me, Knockout?!
明白我的意思了吗 击倒？
Explicitly, lord Megatron.
呃…遵命 威震天陛下
Now, since the unfortunate loss of Breakdown has left you rather vulnerable,
好吧 鉴于打击不幸牺牲 你势单力薄
you will require appropriate support.
我再给你一个后援
How very... repellant.
您真是…考虑周到
Here's a twist.
情势有变
It would appear that the Decepticons have retreated from Manhattan.
看上去霸天虎似乎从曼哈顿撤出了
They just... up and left?
他们就这么…放弃离开了？
It is more likely that Megatron has already set course for the second set of coordinates,
看上去更像威震天已经派出部队进入了地下
having dispatched a unit to this relic's underground location.
而他自己赶去第二个坐标处了
Without busting up a city block to get to it?
不用摧毁那片城区吗？
They used subway tunnels.
他们走了地铁隧道
New York has a whole network of them running beneath the city.
纽约有完善的地铁网络贯穿整个城市地下
Since the human population no longer seems to be directly threatened,
既然人类并没有受到直接威胁
maintaining our disguise will be necessary.
那么我们仍需保持隐蔽行动
Arcee, Bumblebee,
阿尔茜 大黄蜂
you are the best choices to navigate through such a densely populated area.
你们是去这种人口密集地区的最佳人选
Optimus, New York has more than 8 million people.
擎天柱？纽约有八百多万人口
The odds of being spotted by at least one of them are pretty high,
即使在地下活动
even if they are headed underground.
被发现的可能性也很大
Where are you going with this?
你说这话什么意思？
You're gonna need a face man.
他们需要个代理人
Someone who can speak on their behalf.
得有人替他们应付局面
A human who can run interference if their cover gets blown.
一个在他们暴露时可以提供掩护的人
Well, I've actually been in subway stations.
我进过地铁站
I grew up in a major metropolis,
我就生长在一座大都会城市
unlike Mr. "I've never been outside Jasper, Nevada".
而不像某位“从来没离开过内华达贾斯帕”先生
I have been to Cybertron.
我可去过塞博特恩
Cybertron doesn't have subways.
塞博特恩没有地铁！
Does it?
是吧？
Agent Fowler's field experience makes him our best candidate.
从实战经验来看 福勒探员是最佳人选
If he weren't still recovering for his encounter with the Decepticon warship.
可惜他还没从霸天虎战舰的遭遇中恢复过来
Which we survived without incident.
而我们却安然无事！这不是偶然！
Very well. Miko and Jack will accompany Arcee and Bumblebee.
好吧 神子和杰克陪大黄蜂还有阿尔茜前往
Yes!
太好了！
Initiate transport,
开始传送
and triangulate coordinates of the other three relics.
同时开始定位另外三组坐标
Of course, it's no Cybertron...
早说这儿跟塞博特恩不一样吧
All right, face, how do we get underground?
好吧代理人 我们怎么进入地下
Well, you can't just jump the turnstiles and hope no one notices.
这个 显然你们不能指望 直接通过地铁闸门而不被别人注意到
Check it out! Construction.
看这边！工地！
A fact of life in the big city.
大城市总少不了这个
Bumblebee, don't move!
别动 大黄蜂！
The third rail.
输电轨
It carries electricity to power the subway trains.
它是给地铁输送电能的
One touch and zap! You're fried.
只要碰一下 噗兹 烧焦你
He must have learned about that on TV or something.
他一定是从什么电视节目上学到的这些
Could we please pick up the pace?
我们能再快点吗？
The humidity down here is threatening to corrode my undercarriage.
这里的湿气会侵蚀我的底盘的
Must you hover?!
能别老哼哼 行吗？
Are we getting any closer?
我们接近了吗？
Triangulating the coordinates is one thing...
准确定位坐标不难
but figuring out how to reach them through this maze is another.
难的是在这个迷宫里找到通路
Drilling.
钻孔声
It's coming from this way!
是从这边传来的！
Miko!
神子！
Miko, what is your...
神子 你怎么…？
Hold it right there!
在那边别动！
- Scrap.
- 见鬼！
What are you kids doing down here?
你们两个小鬼在这下面做什么？
We're... on a field trip... with our school.
我们是跟学校来郊游的
But we got lost.
但是我们走丢了
Oh, really?
噢 是吗？
I told him we should stay with our group,
我跟他说过 我们应该跟上同伴
but Leonard here insisted we search for fossils.
但是“伦纳德”坚持要去找化石
My bad.
我的错
I want to go home.
我想回家…
Can you help us, mister...
…你能帮我们吗 您是…
Vogel. But you can call me Vogel.
沃莫 叫我沃格也行
So, ever ride a sweeper train?
那么 有没有乘坐过清洁工火车？
Face.
掩护
And this section was added in the '30s
这一段是三十年代建造的
as part of a public-works project.
当时公共工程的一部分
Fascinating.
真…漂亮…
But these old tunnels have a dark side, too.
这些老隧道也有阴暗的一面
Strange creatures have been said to lurk down here.
据说有怪异的生物潜伏在这里：
Giant snakes, albino alligators, even mole men.
巨蟒 白色短吻鳄 甚至还有鼹鼠人
Well, but those are just people who live down here
那不过是些流浪汉无家可归
because they have no place else to go, right?
才住在这下面 不是吗？
That's what the media wants you to believe.
那不过是媒体宣传的
But I say, they're from outer space.
但要我说 他们来自外太空
I'm telling you,
我告诉你们
Area 51's got nothing on this place.
这些都不是51区干的
The aliens are down here,
外星人在这下面呢！
building up their army,
他们在组建军队
plotting to use us humans as slave labor.
说不定抓了人类做苦役
Aliens, huh? Hahaha... If he only knew.
外星人？哈哈哈 但愿他知道…
I'm picking up a locator beacon.
我收到一个定位信号
The 'Cons have unearthed the relic.
虎子们已经挖出了圣物
Well? Let me see it already!
快拿给我看看
Lock and load.
准备交火
Attack, already!
还愣着干什么！
I'll get the relic!
我去抢圣物
You have lovely features,
你的脸蛋很漂亮
perfect for a painful little procedure I call  the "nip and tuck".
正适合来搞一个 我称之为“呲牙裂嘴”的痛苦小实验
Dodge and kick.
回旋踢！
Shock and drop.
电倒你！
This way.
这边！
How do you know?
你怎么知道的？
Miko, let's think this through.
神子 让我们好好想想
Why? 'Cause you think I don't know what I'm doing?
为什么？你觉得我不知道自己在做什么？
"I'm Jack! Optimus picked me to go to Cybertron, so I must know everything!"
“我是杰克 擎天柱派我去塞博特恩 所以我肯定什么都懂！”
Okay, Miko, seriously...
好了神子 你真这么想？
if that's what's bugging you, then why didn't you say something before?
如果那就是你的烦心事 那之前为什么不说？
I've been holding it in.
我在努力克制
Since when do you hold anything in?
你还会克制？
Look, it's not like you don't contribute.
你看 这不是说你就没有贡献
Just yesterday, you helped take down a psychotic Decepticon warship.
就在昨天 你还帮忙击落了一艘发了神经的霸天虎飞船！
This isn't a competition!
这不是在竞赛！
Lost, huh?
迷路了 哈？
You two are gonna have to explain yourselves to the New York transit authority.
你们俩得跟纽约交通管理部门解释清楚！
I think we should tell him the truth.
我想我们应该说出真相
Right.
好吧
The truth is... we lost our dog.
事实上…我们弄丢了我们的狗
You're wasting your breath.
你在白费口舌！
The real truth.
真正的真相！
We're trying to prevent aliens
我们需要阻止外星人
from digging up a powerful ancient relic so they can't use it to destroy our planet.
不能让他们挖出一种远古的强力武器 否则我们的星球会被毁灭！
I swore I heard something weird and high-pitched earlier today...
我就觉得今天早些时候我听到了奇怪的声音
something that wasn't the crew drilling over on track 5.
在五号道挖掘的那些肯定不是施工队！
Now, shall we see precisely what you are and what you do?
现在 让我们来看看你到底是个啥 有啥作用
And what better way to learn your power
除了进行活体试验
than to conduct an on-site experiment?
还有什么更好的方法呢？
Mole men! Metal ones!
鼹鼠人！金属的！
Actually, Decepticons.
事实上 是霸天虎
And they have Arcee and Bumblebee.
他们抓住了阿尔茜和大黄蜂！
Vogel, this thing have another gear?
沃格 这玩意儿还能开得更快吗？
Abso-Freakin'-Lutely!
当然能！
Hey! Watch the finish!
嘿！小心我的喷漆！
Hate to run, but I just missed my train.
我也不喜欢逃跑 不过我得去赶火车了！
Follow the relic. I'll grab Jack and Miko.
去追圣物 我去带回杰克和神子！
Not good. Brake line must have been torched.
不太妙！一定是刹车线坏了！
We can't stop?
没法刹车？
No big deal.
没关系
These tracks go around for miles, right, Vogel?
这条轨道有几英里长 不是吗 沃格？
Not this one.
这条不是！
This track dead-ends, as in crash and burn?
这条是死路？就是说我们会撞毁？
I'm really starting to hate trains!
我真的开始讨厌火车了！
What was that?
那是什么?
Welcome to Earth!
欢迎来到地球！
Vogel, no!
沃格 不要！
She's one of the good guys!
她是好人！
Arcee, the brakes are shot!
阿尔茜 刹车失灵了！
Is there any kind of emergency override?
有备用控制吗？
N-No, ma'am!
没有 女士
But there is a switch-track control up ahead.
不过前方有个扳道闸门
If you can just adjust the pole rod...
只要拉动拉杆就行
You'll know it when you see it. It'll re-route us to another line.
看见你就明白了 可以转到另外一条轨道
Did she just turn into... a motorcycle?
她变成了一辆…摩托车？
Uh-Oh.
啊哦
And that would be?
那个是？
Trouble.
坏蛋
Well, well, look who got his treads back.
哇哦 看看是谁又能变形了
Scrap!
见鬼！
- Yes! - Alright! - Sweet!
- 耶！ - 好极了！ - 太棒了！
Come to mama.
到妈妈这儿来
Shock and drop.
电倒你
We're in the clear.
呼 前面畅通无阻
Still need a way to stop...
可我们还是得停下来
beside slamming into a wall, I mean.
而不是一头撞上墙
Watch out!
小心！
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂！
Dude!
哥们！
How did you not get mashed?
你怎么…没被撞到？
Phase shifter.
相位仪
Handy when you need to pass through solid objects. Or vice versa.
可以让你穿过实体 或者让实体穿过你
No. No!!!
不 不！
You scratch my face, I scratch yours!
你们刮花了我的脸 我要你们好看！
He knows. Do we have to take him with us?
他都知道了 我们需要把他带上吗？
To the mother ship?
上母舰？
I think I have a work-around.
我有个妙计
That's right, soldier!
没错 战士
Dump that rock and come on home!
扔了那块石头 快点回来！
Fowler. Miko, what is it? What in the sam hill?
我是福勒 神子？什么事？什么？
I'm in the middle of a crisis here, and you want me to...
我正在处理危急事件 你却要我…
... put him on the line.
…让他接电话
Mr. Vogel, this is special agent William Fowler of the United States government.
沃格先生 我是美国政府特工福勒
You are hereby deputized as an honorary agent for the department of, um...
你特此被任命为星际关系部的 嗯…
interstellar relations.
荣誉探员
Thank you, sir.
谢谢您 长官！
So... you folks will be in touch?
那么…我们保持联系？
Abso-Freakin'-Lutely!
当然
But until then,
啊啊 不过我们得保持无线电静默
we need to maintain complete radio silence.
除非我们主动联系你
It's been an honor.
这是我的荣幸
Good call, face.
点子不错 代理人
Eh, I understand big-city people... who spend way too much time below ground.
哼 我了解大城市居民 他们在地下呆太久了
One relic down, three to go.
找到一个圣物 还剩三个
Let's hope the others are having similar results.
但愿其他人也有好消息
Robots who turn into vehicles.
变成交通工具的机器人
Hmm...
那么…